const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Lesion of the dorsal column results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of temperature sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Motor ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory ataxia","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of pain sensations","bool":false},{"option":"Apraxia","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Where does the superior sagittal sinus drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Longitudinal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Right transverse sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Straight sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sinusoidal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is an autoimmune disease affecting the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD)","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":true},{"option":"Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Guillain-Barr√© syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Serotonin or 5-hydroxytryptamine is synthesized from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tri-carboxylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false},{"option":"Tri-acyl glycerol","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What does a 'cobweb' appearance of the CSF indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Viral meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Viral encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Neurosyphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyogenic meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which one of the following forms the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle cells","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What is the biologically active amine form of phenylalanine?","answers":[{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptamine","bool":false},{"option":"Taurine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which nucleus of the hypothalamus is involved in the regulation of thirst and hunger?","answers":[{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Supraoptic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"In a T2WI section magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), the cerebrospinal fluid appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bright","bool":true},{"option":"Grey","bool":false},{"option":"Jet black","bool":false},{"option":"Dark","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following happens in Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"D3 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D1 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"D2 receptors are destroyed","bool":false},{"option":"Dopaminergic neurons are destroyed","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following waves are seen when a person is awake and is alert?","answers":[{"option":"Theta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Delta waves","bool":false},{"option":"Beta waves","bool":true},{"option":"Low voltage spindles","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha waves","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Association fibers are the nerve fibers that connect different regions within the same hemisphere. Which of the following is categorized as the association fiber?","answers":[{"option":"Fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Cingulum","bool":true},{"option":"External capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"To which of the following classes do the endorphins belong?","answers":[{"option":"Amine","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Catecholamines","bool":false},{"option":"Monoamine","bool":false},{"option":"Peptide","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is associated with increased dopamine levels?","answers":[{"option":"Global aphasia without hemiparesis","bool":false},{"option":"Schizophrenia","bool":true},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Agnosia","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is not derived from tyrosine?","answers":[{"option":"Serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Acetylcholine increases the permeability of which of the following ions when it binds to nicotinic receptors at the postsynaptic neuron?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Damage to which structure causes Parkinson's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Hemiballismus is caused due to damage to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Putamen","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Caudate","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"The posterior grey horn of the spinal cord develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Floor plate","bool":false},{"option":"Roof plate","bool":false},{"option":"Sulcus limitans","bool":false},{"option":"Basal plate","bool":false},{"option":"Alar plate","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following glial cells is not derived from the neuroectoderm?","answers":[{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Microglial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following thalamic nuclei receives sensory afferents from the face and mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Ventro-posterior lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Ventro-posterior medial","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral dorsal","bool":false},{"option":"Pulvinar","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 60-year-old hypertensive male was taken to the emergency department with complaints of sudden onset of nausea and vomiting. The examination revealed slurred speech and dysmetria on finger-to-nose test on the left side. However, his gait was normal. In which of the following areas lesion has occurred?","answers":[{"option":"Right flocculonodular lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Right cerebellar hemisphere","bool":false},{"option":"Left cerebellar hemisphere","bool":true},{"option":"Fastigial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A radiologist, while reading the computed tomography scan, noticed a jugular tubercle grooved by IX, X, and XI cranial nerves. This tubercle is part of which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"An 80-year-old male came to the hospital with a head injury due to a bad fall. He had a stylomastoid fracture. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 45-year-old female is in recovery from a stroke. She is found to have difficulty in speech. She can write the words and can understand their meanings but is unable to produce words. Where is the cerebral cortical area responsible for the above-stated condition located?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":true},{"option":"Superior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What are the commissural fibers associated with the olfactory pathway called?","answers":[{"option":"Hippocampal commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus callosum","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which one of the following arteries supplies the medulla oblongata?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries supply the corpus striatum and internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebellar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior communicating artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Auditory fibers run in the lateral lemniscus terminate in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Crus cerebri","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Medial leminiscus","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is present anterior to the interventricular foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior column of fornix","bool":true},{"option":"Septum pellucidum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior end of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior column of fornix","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Gray rami communicans are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior horn of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Adjacent ganglion of sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral horn of spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Paravertebral ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior root ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following can be caused by an infarction of the genu of the internal capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Visual impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Agitation","bool":false},{"option":"Dysarthria","bool":true},{"option":"Confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory deficits","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following cells line the central canal?","answers":[{"option":"Microglia","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is the correct option regarding the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Purkinje neurons are of bipolar variety","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle connects cerebellum to pons","bool":false},{"option":"Stellate and basket cells are present in the molecular layer","bool":true},{"option":"Molecular, granular, and pyramidal layers are present in cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Purkinje cells have scarce branching","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"The cuneocerebellar pathway conveys information from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Muscles and joints of upper limb and upper part of thorax","bool":true},{"option":"Mid brain","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles and joints of trunk and lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles and joints of upper and lower limb","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"During resting, the heart rate is slowed, pupils are constricted, peristalsis and glandular activity are increased, sphincters are opened, and the bladder wall is contracted. Which of the following system is activated in this state?","answers":[{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Meroanencephaly is defined as the partial absence of the brain. It is caused by which of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Defect in regionalization","bool":false},{"option":"Disorder of myelination","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of closure of anterior neuropore","bool":true},{"option":"Failure of neural crest cells formation","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of closure of posterior neuropore","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Cystic mass containing meninges with CSF only protrudes at the thoracolumbar region of a newborn. This cystic mass would be classified as which of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida occulta","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida aperta","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida cystica with meningocele","bool":true},{"option":"Spina bifida cystica with meningomylocele","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Basal nuclei are a collection of cell bodies that control voluntary movements. Which of the following vesicles gives rise to basal nuclei?","answers":[{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A vascular lesion of the primary visual area (Brodmann area 17) may cause which one of the following defects?","answers":[{"option":"Binasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia with macular sparing","bool":true},{"option":"Blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral homonymous hemianopia","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 20-year-old girl presented with severe weight loss. On history, she admitted that her appetite is greatly reduced and she is experiencing sleep disturbances for the last two months. Which hypothalamic nucleus controls the appetite center?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nuclei","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Medial hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior hypothalamic nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following tract conveys information about highly localized touch\r\nsensations and proprioception?","answers":[{"option":"Spino-reticular tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column tract","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A patient loses the sensation of crude touch, while the sensation of fine touch is intact. Which of the following tracts is most likely to be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal column tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Spino-reticular tract","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A lesion in the dorsal column tract causes loss of proprioception resulting in severe ataxia. It can be confirmed by which of the following signs?","answers":[{"option":"Positive Romberg's test","bool":true},{"option":"Exaggerated tendon reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of tendon reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Tremors","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Babinski's sign","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A lesion in which of the following nuclei in the hypothalamus causes hypothalamic obesity?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorso-medial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-optic nucleus nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-chiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following hypothalamic nuclei acts as the body's primary circadian pacemaker?","answers":[{"option":"Ventromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorso-medial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-chiasmatic nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Supra-optic nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is mostly associated with slow-wave sleep?","answers":[{"option":"Irregular heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Dreaming","bool":false},{"option":"High frequency EEG waves","bool":false},{"option":"Memory","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep terrors","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Prolonged rapid eye movement (REM) sleep deprivation can result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Impaired driving","bool":false},{"option":"Teeth grinding","bool":false},{"option":"Increased appetite","bool":false},{"option":"Sleep terrors","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired memory","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Maintaining working memory contents for a dozen seconds requires which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medial temporal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Young children can immediately repeat short sentences spoken by their parents and siblings, and also produce new sentences that follow the rules of their native language. The ability to produce new, rule-governed sentences is thought to involve which kind of learning?","answers":[{"option":"Short-term","bool":false},{"option":"Explicit","bool":false},{"option":"Working","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term","bool":false},{"option":"Implicit","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male presents to the emergency department after a road traffic accident. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) shows damage to the corticospinal tract on one side. Which of the following tract serves as an \"alternative pathway\" for transmitting motor signals to the spinal cord?","answers":[{"option":"Tectospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Rubrospinal tract","bool":true},{"option":"Reticulospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Olivospinal tract","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"The sweat glands and piloerector muscles of hairy skin are innervated by which of the following fiber types?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenergic postganglionic sympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic postganglionic parasympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic preganglionic sympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic preganglionic parasympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic postganglionic sympathetic","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which type of cholinergic receptor is found at synapses between preganglionic and postganglionic neurons of the sympathetic system?","answers":[{"option":"Muscarinic","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 2","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotinic","bool":true},{"option":"Beta 1","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following nerve fiber types is most sensitive to anesthetic agents?","answers":[{"option":"C fibers","bool":true},{"option":"A delta fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A gamma fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A alpha fibers","bool":false},{"option":"B fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which one of the following is the capability of the brain to ignore unimportant information?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitation","bool":false},{"option":"Reverberation","bool":false},{"option":"Consolidation","bool":false},{"option":"Sensitization","bool":false},{"option":"Habituation","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A patient presents with the inability to interpret thoughts, although he is capable of expressing individual words or even short phrases. Which area of the brain is most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":true},{"option":"Angular gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Exner's area","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"During the removal of a brain tumor in a patient, a part of the brain was removed. Upon successful awakening, the patient is unable to form new memories. However, he can recall most previously learned memories satisfactorily. Which of the brain area may have been affected during the operation?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior hypothalamic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following functions is the result of an increased activity of the sympathetic nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary constriction","bool":false},{"option":"Gallbladder emptying","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation for near vision","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolar dilation","bool":true},{"option":"Penile erection","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Long-term potentiation is identified in hippocampal mossy fibers by an increase in which of the following ions in the postsynaptic area?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorus","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"During an examination of a young boy, the child feels very ticklish so it becomes difficult for the doctor to examine him. Which of the following tract carries the above sensation?","answers":[{"option":"Corticospinal tract","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral spinothalamic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior spinothalamic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal column medial leminiscal system","bool":false},{"option":"Spinocerebellar tract","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"During suturing of a wound, a patient receives local anesthesia around the wound area. After this, he did not feel any needle pain during suturing. Which of the following option could be the reason for this?","answers":[{"option":"Blockage of voltage-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of ligand-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of ligand-gated K‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Early closure of voltage-gated Na‚Å∫ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of voltage-gated K‚Å∫ channels","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following sensations are relayed at the ventral posterolateral nuclei of the thalamus before reaching the post-central gyrus?","answers":[{"option":"Somatic afferents from head and arms","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic afferents from trunk and limbs","bool":true},{"option":"Visceral afferents from gut","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral afferents from gut","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic afferents from head and limbs","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Secretion of melatonin by the pineal gland is regulated by which one of the following parts of the diencephalon?","answers":[{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Epithalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":true},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Metathalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme of acetylcholine synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Phenylalanine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline acetyl transferase","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Aminotransferase","bool":false},{"option":"Choline esterase","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What is the reason that brain tissue cannot utilize fatty acids for energy?","answers":[{"option":"Enzymes of beta-oxidation are present in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"They are not found in brain tissue","bool":false},{"option":"They cannot pass through blood-brain barrier","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids are attached with albumin in blood","bool":true},{"option":"They are utilized in ganglioside formation","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A compound that is synthesized in a neuron, has a receptor in vicinity, and has agonists and antagonists defines which of the following terms?","answers":[{"option":"Neurohormone","bool":false},{"option":"Neuromediator","bool":false},{"option":"Neuropeptide","bool":false},{"option":"Neurochemical mediator","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotransmitter","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Practicing a healthy lifestyle by eating a diet rich in fruits and vegetables, and maintaining a healthy weight for the prevention of hypertension and stroke is advised by physicians. Which one of the following preventions is applied here?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary","bool":false},{"option":"Quarternary","bool":false},{"option":"Primary","bool":true},{"option":"Primordial","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A surgeon working in a private rehabilitation facility encounters a patient with a certain tumor that responds only to radiotherapy and surgery. The surgeon is enthusiastic to perform the surgery and proceeds to convince the patient to perform the surgery despite the lack of evidence of surgery being the better option. Which of the following principles of ethical communication has the surgeon breached in the above scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false},{"option":"Honesty and truthfulness","bool":true},{"option":"Equity and justice","bool":false},{"option":"Active listening","bool":false},{"option":"Empathy","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding the mu receptor stimulation?","answers":[{"option":"Analgesia (spinal)","bool":false},{"option":"Sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory depression","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 39-year-old woman has had a severe headache for 3 days. On physical examination,\r\nshe is afebrile and normotensive. Fundoscopic examination shows papilledema on the\r\nright. One day later, she has right pupillary dilation and impaired ocular movement. Which of the following lesions best explains these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Transtentorial medial temporal herniation","bool":true},{"option":"Ruptured middle cerebral berry aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic subdural hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus ex vacuo","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"An 85-year-old male is in a coma in a hospital. His daughter makes all the decisions regarding his treatment on his behalf. Which of the following options best describes the type of consent in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Surrogate consent","bool":true},{"option":"Expressed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Informed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Opt-out consent","bool":false},{"option":"Implied consent","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 15-year-old girl presented to the outpatient department with complaints of headaches for the past 8 months. Over a 2-week period, she has a generalized seizure. On physical examination, there is no papilledema or movement disorder. Computed tomography (CT) scan of the head shows a 2 cm mass in the right frontal lobe and shows evidence of recent and remote hemorrhage. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Organizing abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriovenous malformation","bool":true},{"option":"Prior head trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured saccular aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Angiosarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is a modifiable risk factor for stroke?","answers":[{"option":"Genetics","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Peripheral nerves are often damaged in many different forms of different vasculitis including polyarteritis nodosa (PAN), Churg-Strauss syndrome, and Wegener‚Äôs granulomatosis. Which of the following is the most common clinical picture in these disorders?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of sensation in limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Combination neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Mononeuritis multiplex","bool":true},{"option":"Polyneuropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"As a medical professional, you have to come up with ideas for research that are original, unique, new, and relevant to your field of practice. This involves creative thinking. Which of the following will you follow?","answers":[{"option":"Preparation, accommodation, assimilation, centration, egocentrism","bool":false},{"option":"Incubation, preparation, revision, accommodation, centration","bool":false},{"option":"Assimilation, centration, egocentrism, incubation, revision","bool":false},{"option":"Preparation, incubation, illumination, evaluation, implementation","bool":true},{"option":"Accommodation, centration, egocentrism, incubation, revision","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Ali saw a snake and he started trembling. The statement that Ali is afraid because he trembled is better explained by which of the following theories?","answers":[{"option":"Cannon-Bard theory","bool":false},{"option":"James-Lange theory","bool":true},{"option":"Darwin's theory","bool":false},{"option":"Two-factor theory","bool":false},{"option":"Appraisal theory","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Destructive lesion of the Wernicke's area results in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Global aphasia","bool":false},{"option":"Astereognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Agraphia","bool":false},{"option":"Receptive aphasia","bool":true},{"option":"Expressive aphasia","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which nerve exits the skull from the internal acoustic meatus along with the vestibulocochlear nerve (CN VIII)?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve (CN X)","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve (CN VII)","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve (CN V)","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve (CN IX)","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve (CN VI)","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What is the absolute contraindication of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)?","answers":[{"option":"Allergies","bool":false},{"option":"Dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Claustrophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Indwelling cardiac pace maker","bool":true},{"option":"Movement Disorders","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 25-year-old male is brought to the emergency department with complaints of all four\r\nlimbs weakness for 3 days with a history of diarrhea 3 weeks before. On examination, he has flaccid areflexic quadriparesis and the sensations are intact with downgoing plantar. What should be the diagnostic investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve conduction studies","bool":true},{"option":"Serum electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid detailed report (CSF DR)","bool":false},{"option":"MRI cervical spines","bool":false},{"option":"CT brain","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 20-year-old male presented to the neurology outpatient department with complaints of bilateral lower limb weakness and urinary incontinence for the last 4 days. On examination, he had decreased power in both lower limbs with increased tone, brisk reflex, and upgoing plantar. The sensory level was found at the xiphisternum. What is the most likely neurological localization in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Peripheral nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Brain stem","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior horn cells","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Vitamin K reverses the overdose of which of the following agents?","answers":[{"option":"Warfarin","bool":true},{"option":"Unfractionated heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Eptifibatide","bool":false},{"option":"Tirofiban","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"What is the major advantage of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) over computed tomography (CT) scan?","answers":[{"option":"Quick modality","bool":false},{"option":"Does not require any prior preparation","bool":false},{"option":"Superior in detection of calcified lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Use of ionization radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Excellent soft tissue imaging with high contrast sensitivity","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 35-year-old housewife presents to the neurology clinic for evaluation of persistent headache and vomiting for one week with intermittent clouding of consciousness and confusion. She had a prior history of weight loss and fever for the past two months. Two years back, she was treated for pulmonary tuberculosis and became asymptomatic. On examination, signs of meningeal irritation are positive with bilateral papilledema. MRI brain contrast suggests central nervous system tuberculosis. Cerebrospinal fluid detailed report is awaited. What is the most appropriate next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Start anti-tuberculous therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Start anti-fungals","bool":false},{"option":"Start steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for CSF report","bool":false},{"option":"Get an EEG done","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A child is brought to the emergency room with complaints of severe vomiting and seizures. A radiologic scan revealed dilation of the fourth ventricle. Which of the following structures form(s) the floor of the fourth ventricle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of the pons and medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cerebellar peduncle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior surface of cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and inferior medullary velum","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 55-year-old male patient presents to the neurology clinic with the complaint of not being able to acknowledge the left side of his body. He does not wash, shave, or use the left side of his body. A lesion in which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is the most likely cause for this deficit in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Primary somesthetic area","bool":false},{"option":"Prefrontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary somesthetic area","bool":false},{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Somesthetic association area","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with low levels of gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)?","answers":[{"option":"Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Increased pain sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Anxiety","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following statements distinguishes the optic nerve from the optic tract?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve is a part of peripheral nervous system while optic tract is a part of central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has only ipsilateral fibers while optic tract has only contralateral fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has Schwann cells while optic tract has oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve is unmyelinated while optic tract is myelinated","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve has only ipsilateral fibers while the optic tract has both ipsilateral and contralateral fibers","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 35-year-old man is brought to the emergency room after he suffers a head injury in a road traffic accident. It is observed that he has flailing movement in his left upper limb. Which of the following structures is the most likely site of lesion in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Subthalamus","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 42-year-old woman suffered a head injury in a road traffic accident. She was brought to the emergency room and underwent an MRI scan, which revealed a hemorrhage in the inferior frontal gyrus. Which of the following symptoms is the most likely manifestation of a lesion in this area of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Inability to speak whole words","bool":true},{"option":"Paralysis of pharynx and larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of the upper limb","bool":false},{"option":"Deviation of the eyes to side of lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Inability to grasp objects with her hands","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"The craniosacral outflow constitutes the parasympathetic nervous system. The parasympathetic fibers of which of the following nerves control the pupillary and accommodation reflexes?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 45-year-old woman suffers from a stroke and has difficulty with speech. She can write and understand speech but is unable to produce any words. The area affected in this case is located in which of the following gyri of the cerebral cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Precentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior frontal gyrus","bool":true},{"option":"Superior temporal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior frontal gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle frontal gyrus","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following types of neurons innervate extrafusal muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha motor neurons","bool":true},{"option":"A-delta neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma motor neurons","bool":false},{"option":"C type nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"A-beta neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following types of nerve fibers innervate Golgi tendon organs?","answers":[{"option":"Ib sensory afferents","bool":true},{"option":"II sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"III sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"IV sensory afferents","bool":false},{"option":"Ia sensory afferents","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is an opioid receptor antagonist used as a drug for opioid overdose and toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Nalbuphine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Buprenorphine","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Fentanyl","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following neurotransmitters equally excites both alpha and beta-adrenergic receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 55-year-old man with a history of resting tremors in his right hand dies in a road traffic accident and undergoes an autopsy. His neurological examination is likely to reveal degeneration of neurons in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Left corpus striatum","bool":false},{"option":"Left globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Left substantia nigra","bool":true},{"option":"Right globus pallidus","bool":false},{"option":"Right substantia nigra","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following statements correctly describes the main function of the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Detects changes in the chemical composition of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"Supplies nutrition to and prevents hazardous substances from reaching the brain","bool":true},{"option":"Acts as a shock absorber","bool":false},{"option":"Secretes cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A child suffers from non-communicating hydrocephalus. Which of the following is a characteristic of non-communicating hydrocephalus?","answers":[{"option":"Post-hemorrhagic","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased absorption of CSF","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of cerebral aqueduct","bool":true},{"option":"Post-infectious","bool":false},{"option":"Increased absorption of CSF","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 65-year-old male suffers from a cerebrovascular accident. An MRI scan reveals a lesion in the left internal capsule. Which of the following signs or symptoms is most likely to be observed in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Flaccid paralysis in left leg","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccid paralysis in right leg","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis in right leg","bool":true},{"option":"Hyporeflexia in left leg","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis in left leg","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following opioid drugs is used to treat diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Loperamide","bool":true},{"option":"Levorphanol","bool":false},{"option":"Morphine","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone","bool":false},{"option":"Methadone","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following Brodmann's areas corresponds to the motor speech area of Broca?","answers":[{"option":"Brodmann area 44","bool":true},{"option":"Brodmann area 7","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 17","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 22","bool":false},{"option":"Brodmann area 41","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 67-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with complaints of not being able to shrug his shoulders and move his head from side to side over the last few days. Which of the following nerves is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following disorders is characterized by excessive daytime sleepiness and sudden loss of muscle tone?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Somnolence","bool":false},{"option":"Cataplexy","bool":false},{"option":"Alzheimer's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Narcolepsy","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following cell structures constitute the white matter of the central nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Cell bodies only","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Cell bodies and dendrites","bool":false},{"option":"Axons only","bool":false},{"option":"Axons and glial cells","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following terms correctly describes the diphtheria toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Exotoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Neurotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most appropriate intervention after a child has been diagnosed with paralytic poliomyelitis?","answers":[{"option":"Awareness","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccination","bool":false},{"option":"Nutritional supplementation","bool":false},{"option":"Rehabilitation","bool":true},{"option":"Health education","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"While operating on the pituitary gland, a surgeon tries to secure the optic chiasma. Which of the following structures separates the pituitary gland from the optic chiasm?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragmatic sellae","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsum sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculum sellae","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which part of the nervous system consists of two ganglionated nerve trunks extending the entire length of the vertebral column on both sides?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"Parasympathetic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following structures connects Wernicke's area to Broca's area?","answers":[{"option":"Internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Habenular commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior commissure","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate fasciculus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior commissure","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 56-year-old woman presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of not being able to understand spoken language. She can, however, interpret written symbols and speech. Which of the following areas of the cerebral cortex is most likely to be damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Wernicke's area","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary auditory area","bool":true},{"option":"Primary visual area","bool":false},{"option":"Primary auditory area","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary visual area","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following is an active efflux transporter in the blood-brain barrier?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT-1","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT-3","bool":false},{"option":"P-glycoprotein","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT-4","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT-2","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Heparin binds to which of the following molecules to produce its anti-coagulant effect?","answers":[{"option":"Protein C","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-thrombin III","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand factor","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 55-year-old woman presents to the emergency room with a head injury following a road traffic accident. MRI scans reveal damage to the periaqueductal gray area of the midbrain. A lesion in this area is most likely to result in which of the following signs or symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Increased daytime drowsiness","bool":false},{"option":"Increased alertness and consciousness","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of endogenous pain suppression","bool":true},{"option":"Loss of conscious control of respiration from cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of coordination in the movement of the head and neck","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the cerebellum is involved in planning and coordinating movements?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral zone and dentate nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Intermediate zone and interposed nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis and interposed nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Vermis and fastigial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral zone and fastigial nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A child is born with agenesis of the corpus callosum which is a major commissural fiber. Which of the following findings is most likely to be seen in radiological scans of this child's brain?","answers":[{"option":"Deformed tapetum","bool":false},{"option":"Deformed internal capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Prominent forceps minor","bool":false},{"option":"Deformed lateral ventricles","bool":true},{"option":"Prominent forceps major","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/neuroscience/2022","question":"A 55-year-old man presents to the neurology clinic with the complaint of right-sided weakness of the body and left-sided weakness of the face with the tongue deviating to the left upon protrusion. Which of the following structures is most likely to be affected in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":true}]}]
export default arr